<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kacper Wardega</title>
    <link>https://kwardega.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kacper Wardega</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kwardega.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://kwardega.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwardega.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Kacper is a Ph.D. candidate in the Electrical and Computer Engineering department at Boston University advised by Prof. Wenchao Li. His research focus has been on the design and implementation of reliable cyber-physical systems and security for multi-robot systems. Kacper earned a B.Sc. in Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering and a B.Sc. in Mathematics from Ohio State University in 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://kwardega.com/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwardega.com/publications/</guid>
      <description>Application-Aware Scheduling of Networked Applications over the Low-Power Wireless Bus, Kacper Wardega and Wenchao Li. Design, Automation and Test in Europe (DATE), March 2020. (to appear)
Resilience of Multi-Robot Systems to Physical Masquerade Attacks, Kacper Wardega, Roberto Tron and Wenchao Li. IEEE Workshop on the Internet of Safe Things (SafeThings), May 2019. [post]
Masquerade Attack Detection Through Observation Planning for Multi-Robot Systems, Kacper Wardega, Roberto Tron and Wenchao Li. International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS), May 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resilience of Multi-Robot Systems to Physical Masquerade Attacks</title>
      <link>https://kwardega.com/posts/physical-masquerade-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwardega.com/posts/physical-masquerade-attacks/</guid>
      <description>Abstract:  The advent of autonomous mobile multi-robot systems has driven innovation in both the industrial and defense sectors. The integration of such systems in safety-and security-critical applications has raised concern over their resilience to attack. In this work, we investigate the security problem of a stealthy adversary masquerading as a properly functioning agent. We show that conventional multi-agent pathfinding solutions are vulnerable to these physical masquerade attacks. Furthermore, we provide a constraint-based formulation of multi-agent pathfinding that yields multi-agent plans that are provably resilient to physical masquerade attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Weakly-hard Paradigm for Networked Systems</title>
      <link>https://kwardega.com/posts/exploring-weakly-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwardega.com/posts/exploring-weakly-hard/</guid>
      <description>Abstract:  Networked systems have shown great promises in various cyber-physical applications, such as automotive and transportation systems, smart buildings and infrastructures, and robotic systems. As these systems employ advanced components and interact closely with the dynamic environment, they are often subject to significant disturbances from environment interference, security attacks, and device faults. To ensure system safety, performance and other properties, it is critical to capture these disturbances and reason about their impact at the network level.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>