<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kacper Wardega</title>
    <link>https://kwardega.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kacper Wardega</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kwardega.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Byzantine Resilience at Swarm Scale: A Decentralized Blocklist from Inter-robot Accusations</title>
      <link>https://kwardega.com/publications/dbp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwardega.com/publications/dbp/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: The Weighted-Mean Subsequence Reduced (W-MSR) algorithm, the state-of-the-art method for Byzantine-resilient design of decentralized multi-robot systems, is based on discarding outliers received over Linear Consensus Protocol (LCP). Although W-MSR provides well-understood theoretical guarantees relating robust network connectivity to the convergence of the underlying consensus, the method comes with several limitations preventing its use at scale: (1) the number of Byzantine robots, F, to tolerate should be known a priori, (2) the requirement that each robot maintains 2F+1 neighbors is impractical for large F, (3) information propagation is hindered by the requirement that F+1 robots independently make local measurements of the consensus property in order for the swarm&amp;rsquo;s decision to change, and (4) W-MSR is specific to LCP and does not generalize to applications not implemented over LCP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HoLA Robots: Mitigating Plan-Deviation Attacks in Multi-Robot Systems with Co-Observations and Horizon-Limiting Announcements</title>
      <link>https://kwardega.com/publications/hola/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwardega.com/publications/hola/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Emerging multi-robot systems rely on cooperation between humans and robots, with robots following automatically generated motion plans to service application-level tasks. Given the safety requirements associated with operating in proximity to humans and expensive infrastructure, it is important to understand and mitigate the security vulnerabilities of such systems caused by compromised robots who diverge from their assigned plans. We focus on centralized systems, where a central entity (CE) is responsible for determining and transmitting the motion plans to the robots, which report their location as they move following the plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opportunistic Communication with Latency Guarantees for Intermittently-Powered Devices</title>
      <link>https://kwardega.com/publications/opportunistic-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 11:17:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwardega.com/publications/opportunistic-communication/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Energy-harvesting wireless sensor nodes have found widespread adoption due to their low cost and small form factor. However, uncertainty in the available power supply introduces significant challenges in engineering communications between intermittently-powered nodes. We propose a constraint-based model for energy harvests that together with a hardware model can be used to enable consistent, opportunistic communication with worst-case latency guarantees. We show that greedy approaches that attempt communication whenever energy is available lead to prolonged latencies in real-world environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know the Unknowns: Addressing Disturbances and Uncertainties in Autonomous Systems</title>
      <link>https://kwardega.com/publications/know-the-unknowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 16:45:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwardega.com/publications/know-the-unknowns/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Future autonomous systems will employ complex sensing, computation, and communication components for their perception, planning, control, and coordination, and could operate in highly dynamic and uncertain environment with safety and security assurance. To realize this vision, we have to better understand and address the challenges from the &amp;ldquo;unknowns&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; the unexpected disturbances from component faults, environmental interference, and malicious attacks, as well as the inherent uncertainties in system inputs, model inaccuracies, and machine learning techniques (particularly those based on neural networks).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TrojDRL: Evaluation of Backdoor Attacks on Deep Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://kwardega.com/publications/trojdrl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwardega.com/publications/trojdrl/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: We present TrojDRL, a tool for exploring and evaluating backdoor attacks on deep reinforcement learning agents. TrojDRL exploits the sequential nature of deep reinforcement learning (DRL) and considers different gradations of threat models. We show that untargeted attacks on state-of-the-art actor-critic algorithms can circumvent existing defenses built on the assumption of backdoors being targeted. We evaluated TrojDRL on a broad set of DRL benchmarks and showed that the attacks require only poisoning as little as 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://kwardega.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwardega.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Kacper completed his Ph.D. in Electrical and Computer Engineering at Boston University in 2023. His research focus has been on the design and implementation of reliable cyber-physical systems and security for multi-robot systems. Kacper earned a B.Sc. in Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering and a B.Sc. in Mathematics from Ohio State University in 2016.
Contact ktw@bu.edu
8 St. Mary&amp;rsquo;s St Rm 324, Boston, MA. 02215</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application-Aware Scheduling of Networked Applications over the Low-Power Wireless Bus</title>
      <link>https://kwardega.com/publications/netdag/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwardega.com/publications/netdag/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Recent successes of wireless networked systems in advancing industrial automation and in spawning the Internet of Things paradigm motivate the adoption of wireless networked systems in current and future safety-critical applications. As reliability is key in safety-critical applications, in this work we present NetDAG, a scheduler design and implementation suitable for real-time applications in the wireless setting. NetDAG is built upon the Low-Power Wireless Bus, a high-performant communication abstraction for wireless networked systems, and enables system designers to directly schedule applications under specified task-level real-time constraints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resilience of Multi-Robot Systems to Physical Masquerade Attacks</title>
      <link>https://kwardega.com/publications/physical-masquerade-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwardega.com/publications/physical-masquerade-attacks/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: The advent of autonomous mobile multi-robot systems has driven innovation in both the industrial and defense sectors. The integration of such systems in safety-and security-critical applications has raised concern over their resilience to attack. In this work, we investigate the security problem of a stealthy adversary masquerading as a properly functioning agent. We show that conventional multi-agent pathfinding solutions are vulnerable to these physical masquerade attacks. Furthermore, we provide a constraint-based formulation of multi-agent pathfinding that yields multi-agent plans that are provably resilient to physical masquerade attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Weakly-hard Paradigm for Networked Systems</title>
      <link>https://kwardega.com/publications/exploring-weakly-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwardega.com/publications/exploring-weakly-hard/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Networked systems have shown great promises in various cyber-physical applications, such as automotive and transportation systems, smart buildings and infrastructures, and robotic systems. As these systems employ advanced components and interact closely with the dynamic environment, they are often subject to significant disturbances from environment interference, security attacks, and device faults. To ensure system safety, performance and other properties, it is critical to capture these disturbances and reason about their impact at the network level.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
